## Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Burbank, CA | She/Her/Hers

## **Summary**

Computer Science graduate with a background in Finance, eager to leverage my programming and engineering skills in a professional setting; academic and project experience includes 2 years object-oriented programming, 1 year .NET/C# web development, and 2 years SQL and database administration.

#### **Skills**

Languages: C# | JavaScript

Frameworks: ASP.NET Core | Swashbuckle | Entity Framework Core

Databases: SQL | PostgreSQL | MongoD

Other: Git | Heroku | Postman | Swagger | Splunk | Regex | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap

## **Projects**

## Ifost42/brailleAPI | Creator | Open Source

- .NET REST API, manages a database of ascii braille special symbols as defined by the International Council on English Braille.
- Swagger documentation follows Open API Specification standards.

## Ifost42/blog | Creator | Open Source | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application, used as a knowledge base of .NET(C#) coding and web development articles.
- Implements identity/role based access and rendering to limit article permissions to the owner while allowing users to leave comments.
- Google SMTP email service verifies user registration and forwards contact form submissions to the owner.
- Code-first approach using Entity Framework Core and PostgreSQL.

#### Ifost42/Franchise | Creator | Open Source | Website

- ASP.NET Full stack web application that evaluates the coverage health of a franchise by determining which locations (in a provided csv file) are farthest apart.
- Explores Kruskal's Minimum Spanning Tree to filter locations that can pass through other locations.
- Leveraged Unit tests (TDD) to manage scope changes as the app evolved over time.

#### **Experience**

Benefit Plans Inc, Los Angeles, CA | Employer Services Analyst | 01/2019 - Present

- Developed, implemented, and maintained digital operational procedures that manage \$100M+ in monthly contribution payments to pre-taxed PH&W (pension, health, and welfare) benefit accounts.
- Produced the training knowledge base for the Employer Services department which expedited the onboarding of new employees.
- Eliminated 40% of the processing time needed to reconcile discrepancies by automating the conversion of raw data to readable format using Excel macros and PowerShell scripts.

# Lynda Foster

B'nai Hayim, Sherman Oaks, CA | Technical Coordinator (Contractor) | 04/2018 - 09/2019

- Established a system for financial reporting, database management, and website maintenance to facilitate the merging of two separate organizations.
- Created knowledge base and trained non-technical staff to independently update their website/database, maintain financial records, reconcile bank accounts, and create monthly financial reports using Quickbooks Online.
- Normalized csv data into 1st normal form for migration into an established relational database.

#### Volunteer

Congregation Beth Meier, Studio City, CA | Web Content Manager | 02/2013 - 01/2018

- Created web content on the organization's ongoing and periodic event information to increase engagement among younger families and newer members.
- Perform requirements analysis for the integration of new features and updates to develop solutions in HTML and PHP.

#### Certifications

Splunk Core Power User | ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management | Oracle Database SQL Certified Associate 1Z0-071

#### **Education**

BSc in Computer Science | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT Technologies: C++, Java, Python, MySQL, Machine Learning, Web Development